Richard Mawuli Dzidzornu

Email: rdzidzornu@gmail.com Mobile: 240 455 8150

Clearance Status: Active Secret Clearance and capable of obtaining Top Secret Clearance (TSC)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detailed-oriented individual with over 5 years of experience in database management system and business intelligence tools. Honorably discharged from the United States Navy after serving for a period of 6 years. Currently pursuing Master of Science degree in Applied Data Science at Syracuse University and on the Navy Financial Improvement Program(FIP MAC) project for SECNAV/OPNAV as Data Scientist and ETL Developer.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist/ETL Developer (Snr. Consultant)

Deloitte Consulting LLP

- 11/2019 – Present

Arlington, Virginia

Current Project: SECNAV/OPNAV FIP MAC Project - United States Navy.

Technical Environment:

Python, R-Programming, Tableau Desktop, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL Server Analysis Services, Advance Microsoft Excel, Regression Analysis

Oracle Database/ETL Developer (Snr. Consultant)

Deloitte Consulting LLP

07/2018 - 11/2019

Rosslyn Office, Arlington, Virginia

Project: AE2S - United States Army G8

Army Equipping Enterprise System (AE2S) - The purpose of this project is to create applications to support planning and budgeting process. Informatica Power Center ETL tool is incorporated into the product as an integration platform.

- Designed and developed informatica mappings, sessions, and workflows to load data into staging area and from staging area to target database.
- Developed complex mappings using different transformations like Source Qualifiers, Expressions, Filters, Joiners, Update Strategy, Routers, Union, Lookups and Aggregators.
- Maintained batch scripts and automation jobs.
- Implemented sending Post-Session Email once data is loaded.
- Used Toad for Oracle in Query writing and SQL Loader in trouble shooting.
- Created and documented all conceptual, logical, and physical models for database needs.
- Created and maintained all database objects necessary for the Enterprise Reporting team using IDERA.
- Assisted in creating multiple dashboards for Enterprise Reporting Team.
- Developed SQL scripts to maintain and update the database for applications.
- Good knowledge of Data warehouse concepts and principles (Kimball/Inmon) Star Schema, Snowflake, SCD, Surrogate keys, Normalization/Denormalization.
- Extensively used SQL, PL/SQL in writing Stored Procedures, Functions, Packages, exception handling and Triggers.
- Good exposure in overall SDLC including requirement gathering, development, testing, debugging, deployment, documentation and production support.
- Data profiling, data cleansing, data mapping, data modeling, data validation.

Technical Environment:

Informatica Power Center 10.1.0, Toad for Oracle, SQL Developer, SQL Plus, SQL Loader, Linux, Microsoft SQL Server, Tableau Desktop.

ETL Developer/Auditor

Defense Contract Audit Agency (DCAA) **Columbia, Maryland.**

07/2017 - 07/2018

- Designs SSIS package templates as the base code for package development incorporating package configurations, connection managers and logging in it.
- Implemented package configurations in the development, test, and production environments.
- Created and managed database objects, stored procedures, triggers, views and user defined functions using T-SQL programming language.
- Create and manage SQL Server Agent jobs for data warehouse operations.
- Manage existing ETL strategy to extract, clean and deliver data to OLAP environment and ensure accuracy, consistency, and integrity of the data warehouse.
- Develop and Deploy ETL packages for data migration from various sources such as excel, flat file, access into MS SQL Server using SSIS.
- Perform source to target mapping and implement business logic.
- Monitor SSIS packages using built-in SQL Server report dashboard.
- Work with project managers on business intelligence initiatives, technical requirements and metrics.
- Participate in the development of data warehouse projects.
- Responsible for database architecture, design and development.
- Identified and troubleshot database issues.
- Works on ETL projects implementing Slowly Changing Dimensions using SSIS.
- Facilitates effective communication and coordination between developers and auditors

SQL/SSRS Developer

United States Navy (DoD) McGuire AFB, NJ.

May 2014 – July 2017

- Developed SQL scripts and stored procedures.
- Performed installation and configuration of SQL Server and Report Manager.
- Use SSRS to create audit report and baseline report on aircraft maintenance program for all personnel in the organization, which identified five discrepancies resulting in 100 percent effectiveness of the program.
- Created report to monitored accuracy and timely processing of purchase transactions in order to avoid delays and duplication of orders and purchase requests.
- Created report dashboard to maintain and monitor over 84 tire and wheel qualifications under the Command's Tire and Wheel Maintenance Safety Program ensuring strict compliance with the Naval Aviation Maintenance Program.
- Created report for weekly inventory on aircraft parts for maintenance on five aircrafts worth several billions of dollars and the timely replenishment of parts resulting in zero shortage of maintenance parts.
- Developed weekly and monthly reports for higher-level management decision-making purposes on total purchases.

Aviation Structural Mechanic

United States Navy (DoD) **McGuire AFB, NJ.**

July 2011 – May 2014

Led and trained a team of technicians in hardware/software installations and troubleshooting. Performed preventive and corrective maintenance on state-of-the-art equipment's and briefed senior military leadership on software/hardware use.

Supervision

Supervised 24 Training Officers charged with the management of 220 individual electronic training jackets and processing of all school requests resulting in a 30 percent increase in the organization's mission readiness.

SYSTEM EXPERIENCE

Software / Products: Toad for Oracle (Project Experience), SQL Developer (Project Experience), Informatica Power Center (Project Experience), Putty (Project Experience) Tableau Desktop (Project Experience), Microsoft Access (Project Experience), MS SQL Server (Project Experience), Visio - Project Experience.

Development Tools / Languages: Oracle PL/SQL – Intermediate, T- SQL, Python (Project Experience), R – Programming (Project Experience), Jupyter Notebook (Project Experience) Spyder 3.0 - Project Experience. Hadoop Ecosystem (Academic Experience), Hive (Academic Experience)

General Tools: Microsoft Word, Microsoft Access - Project Experience, Microsoft PowerPoint - Project Experience, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Project - Training Only, MS SQL Server Database 2012/2014/2016, MS Integration Services (SSIS), SQL Server Analysis Services (SSAS), MS Reporting Services (SSRS), Microsoft Excel Pivot Table, Microsoft Power Pivot

EDUCATION

Syracuse University – Master of Science – Applied Data Science 01/2019 - Present

University of Maryland University College, Adelphi, MD - Bachelor of Science - Accounting 12/2013 – 12/2016

University of Ghana, Accra, Ghana - Bachelor of Science - Business Administration 09/2001 - 05/2005

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

MCP – Microsoft Certified Professional
 MCSA – Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate
 Lean Six Sigma – Yellow Belt



VOLUNTEER SERVICE

- Mobile Meals of Norfolk, Non-Profit Organization in Norfolk, Virginia.
 Volunteer 04/2012 07/2015
- American Red Cross Society, Burlington County Chapter, McGuire AFB, New Jersey.
 Member/Volunteer 11/2015 Present.